export const FOODANDNUTRITIONA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The digestion of meat begins in the",
A: "mouth",
B: "stomach",
C: "colon",
D: "duodenum",
answer: "B. stomach",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The process of ensuring a hygienic and healthy environment is called",
A: "cleaning",
B: "ventilation",
C: "aeration",
D: "sanitation",
answer: "D. sanitation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The process of cutting fat from the surface of meat is referred to as",
A: "trimming",
B: "trussing",
C: "slicing",
D: "scraping",
answer: "A. trimming",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. In meat cookery, the papa in unripe pawpaw is used as",
A: "colouring",
B: "flavouring",
C: "tenderizer",
D: "preservative",
answer: "C. tenderizer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. An example of a traditional method of food preservation is",
A: "salting",
B: "bottling",
C: "freezing",
D: "Irradiation",
answer: "A. salting",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. An item used to pierce kebab is called",
A: "knife",
B: "fork",
C: "skewer",
D: "toothpick",
answer: "C. skewer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The process of creating a business for profit making is known as",
A: "shares",
B: "entrepreneurship",
C: "investment",
D: "saving",
answer: "B. entrepreneurship",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. An example of a true berry is",
A: "pear",
B: "date",
C: "grape",
D: "watermelon",
answer: "C. grape",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Foods that require little or no effort in their preparation are referred to as",
A: "convenience foods",
B: "réchauffé foods",
C: "ready to eat",
D: "takeaway",
answer: "A. convenience foods",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The ability of pudding batter to hold air is due to the presence of",
A: "yeast",
B: "baking powder",
C: "bicarbonate of soda",
D: "egg",
answer: "D. egg",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The type of service where food is served from the kitchen is referred to as",
A: "family service",
B: "plate service",
C: "buffet service",
D: "English service",
answer: "C. buffet service",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. An example of a white fish is",
A: "catfish",
B: "mackerel",
C: "cod",
D: "lobster",
answer: "C. cod",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The deficiency disease shown in diagram above is called",
A: "beriberi",
B: "dermatitis",
C: "goitre",
D: "pellagra",
answer: "C. goitre",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following micronutrients is required for the prevention of the diseases?",
A: "Iron",
B: "Iodine",
C: "Potassium",
D: "Sodium",
answer: "B. Iodine",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The function of the nutrient required for the prevention of the disease is",
A: "production of haemoglobin",
B: "secretion of oestrogen",
C: "production of thyroxin",
D: "secretion of pepsin",
answer: "C. production of thyroxin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An example of a food source of the nutrient required for the prevention of the disease is",
A: "fish",
B: "carrot",
C: "meat",
D: "cassava",
answer: "B. carrot",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A person suffering from scurvy should eat foods rich in ascorbic acid",
A: "folic acid",
B: "thiamine",
C: "retinol",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "D. ascorbic acid",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Garnishes are added to dishes basically to improve their",
A: "food value",
B: "appearance",
C: "texture",
D: "flavour",
answer: "B. appearance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. When wheat flour is mixed with liquid, the substance which enables it to stretch and hold gas bubbles is",
A: "casein",
B: "bran",
C: "albumen",
D: "gluten",
answer: "D. gluten",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is an experimental dish?",
A: "jollof rice",
B: "wheat loaf",
C: "ginger-moringa tea",
D: "coffee drink",
answer: "C. ginger-moringa tea",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. When storing fruits and vegetables in a refrigerator, they should be put in",
A: "a paper bag",
B: "an aluminium foil",
C: "a polythene bag",
D: "a cling film",
answer: "A. a paper bag",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Fruits and vegetables act as mild laxative due to their high content of",
A: "citric acid",
B: "mineral elements",
C: "dietary fibre",
D: "ascorbic acid",
answer: "C. dietary fibre",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The most suitable utensil for baking queen cakes is",
A: "baking tray",
B: "cake pan",
C: "loaf tin",
D: "patty tin",
answer: "D. patty tin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A factor to consider when purchasing canned foods is the",
A: "shelf life",
B: "time of the year",
C: "skill of the homemaker",
D: "service of the food",
answer: "A. shelf life",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following dishes is custard based dessert?",
A: "bread and butter pudding",
B: "fruit crumble",
C: "sweet pancake",
D: "pineapple upside down pudding",
answer: "B. fruit crumble",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A suitable fruit for preparing marmalade is",
A: "guava",
B: "pineapple",
C: "orange",
D: "pawpaw",
answer: "C. orange",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In the preparation of fruit drinks, it is best to use",
A: "overripe fruits",
B: "unripe fruits",
C: "ripe and firm fruits",
D: "semi-ripe and soft fruits",
answer: "C. ripe and firm fruits",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In a pressure cooker, the function of the control valve is to",
A: "enable the food withstand the temperature",
B: "ensure that steam does not escape from the cooker",
C: "allow steam to be released from the cooker",
D: "regulate the temperature within the cooker",
answer: "D. regulate the temperature within the cooker",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The function of clove in pineapple drink is to",
A: "sedate",
B: "flavour",
C: "colour",
D: "stimulate",
answer: "B. flavour",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The main purpose of invalid cookery is to",
A: "provide good food",
B: "give enough food energy",
C: "build up tissues",
D: "satisfy patient’s appetite",
answer: "D. satisfy patient’s appetite",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The correct method of preparing chocolate drink is to",
A: "mix chocolate powder with cold liquid, pour boiling water, mix and serve",
B: "add hot liquid to chocolate powder, heat mixture and serve",
C: "add hot liquid to chocolate powder, mix and serve",
D: "mix chocolate powder with cold liquid, pour boiling water, heat mixture and serve",
answer: "B. add hot liquid to chocolate powder, heat mixture and serve",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. In which of the following dishes can egg serve as a thickener?",
A: "Yam balls",
B: "Caramel custard",
C: "Scotch egg",
D: "Castle pudding",
answer: "B. Caramel custard",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The richness of cake depends on the proportion of flour to",
A: "sugar and milk",
B: "egg and fat",
C: "milk and egg",
D: "fat and sugar",
answer: "B. egg and fat",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following spices are used in both sweet and savoury dishes?",
A: "Chilies and nutmeg",
B: "Ginger and cloves",
C: "Mustard and cinnamon",
D: "Paprika and allspice",
answer: "B. Ginger and cloves",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The main reason for using left over boiled rice to prepare rice pudding is to",
A: "reduce cost of food",
B: "change the texture of the rice",
C: "improve the flavour of the rice",
D: "improve the appearance of the rice",
answer: "A. reduce cost of food",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following behaviour combinations portray table etiquette? \nI.   Be on time for meal  \nII.  Do not start eating until everyone is served  \nIII. Lower your head to food when eating  \nIV.  After a meal, place napkin loosely beside the plate",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "I, and IV only",
C: "I, Il and IV only",
D: "II, Ill and IV only",
answer: "C. I, Il and IV only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The best method for re-heating fried fish is",
A: "grilling",
B: "braising",
C: "frying",
D: "stewing",
answer: "A. grilling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Leafy vegetables are best cooked by",
A: "braising",
B: "boiling",
C: "steaming",
D: "stewing",
answer: "C. steaming",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Lemonade, orange drink and pineapple crush are examples of",
A: "distilled drinks",
B: "stimulating drinks",
C: "refreshing drinks",
D: "nourishing drinks",
answer: "C. refreshing drinks",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following is the correct order for a lunch menu presentation?",
A: "Onion soup, jollof rice, fried chicken, fruit salad",
B: "Onion soup, fried chicken, jollof rice, fruit salad",
C: "Fruit salad, onion soup, jollof rice, fried chicken",
D: "Fried chicken, jollof rice, onion soup, fruit salad",
answer: "A. Onion soup, jollof rice, fried chicken, fruit salad",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. In the kitchen, a knife that can serve as an all-purpose cutting tool is the",
A: "palette knife",
B: "vegetable knife",
C: "boning knife",
D: "cook’s knife",
answer: "D. cook’s knife",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Appetizers are to be taken",
A: "in between meals",
B: "at the end of a meal",
C: "just before a meal",
D: "as deserts",
answer: "C. just before a meal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The basic principle in the application of dry heat to cereal is to",
A: "make the gruel lump free",
B: "soften the cellulose",
C: "change starch to dextrin",
D: "gelatinize the starch",
answer: "C. change starch to dextrin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The basic function of mats on a set table is",
A: "for decoration",
B: "to display the class of diners",
C: "to prevent heat marks",
D: "to make the diners comfortable.",
answer: "C. to prevent heat marks",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. An item that must be present in a formal table setting is the",
A: "serving spoon",
B: "napkin",
C: "tray",
D: "cruet set",
answer: "B. napkin",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. A type of flour that requires no sifting before use is called",
A: "instant blending flour",
B: "cake flour",
C: "hard wheat flour",
D: "self-raising flour",
answer: "D. self-raising flour",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following groups of food items have the highest content of dietary fibre",
A: "Cabbage and rice",
B: "Groundnuts and cowpeas",
C: "Orange and oat",
D: "Pineapple and cassava",
answer: "C. Orange and oat",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The function of labels on products is to",
A: "guide consumers to make informed choices",
B: "set standards for the quality of products",
C: "provide information on the cost of products",
D: "make marketing easier for retailers",
answer: "A. guide consumers to make informed choices",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Pellagra is caused by an insufficient intake of",
A: "thiamine",
B: "niacin",
C: "folacin",
D: "riboflavin",
answer: "B. niacin",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The pest found in beans is called",
A: "beetle",
B: "flea",
C: "moth",
D: "weevil",
answer: "D. weevil",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. A product that can be returned to the seller if faulty within a dated period is said to be under",
A: "privilege",
B: "consumer protection",
C: "warranty",
D: "consumer law",
answer: "C. warranty",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. Which of the following vitamins are fat soluble?",
A: "A and B",
B: "A and D",
C: "B and E",
D: "C and D",
answer: "B. A and D",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. Bulk purchase of food items are relatively cheap at",
A: "weekly markets",
B: "shopping malls",
C: "regular markets",
D: "departmental stores",
answer: "A. weekly markets",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. A utensil on which freshly baked foods are placed is called",
A: "oven tray",
B: "bun tin",
C: "baking tray",
D: "cooling rack",
answer: "D. cooling rack",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. One of the disadvantages of hanging curtain at a kitchen window is that it",
A: "absorbs odour",
B: "becomes greasy",
C: "catches fire",
D: "absorbs moisture",
answer: "B. becomes greasy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. An example of food item that must be stored in the freezer compartment of a refrigerator is",
A: "fresh milk",
B: "vegetables",
C: "fruits",
D: "minced meat",
answer: "D. minced meat",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. The most appropriate kitchen linen for cleaning worktables is a",
A: "tea towel",
B: "dish cloth",
C: "food cover",
D: "table cover",
answer: "A. tea towel",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. One of the principles underlying food preservation is to",
A: "purchase foods when in season",
B: "introduce variety into family menu",
C: "wash foods thoroughly",
D: "prevent growth of micro-organisms",
answer: "D. prevent growth of micro-organisms",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. The best utensil for making omelette is a",
A: "poacher",
B: "casserole",
C: "saucepan",
D: "frying pan",
answer: "D. frying pan",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. Greasy kitchen linen are best cleaned with",
A: "brine",
B: "detergent",
C: "bleach",
D: "vinegar",
answer: "A. Cold",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]